Tead, Ordway Papers 5530
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Equalizing Educational Opportunities Beyond the Secondary School, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Ethics in Education, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 26)
- The Evaluation Point of View, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 27)
- The Executive's Reading: Personal Joy and Prof. Asset, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Extra Curricula Challenge in Urban Universities, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Faculty-Administration Relationships in Colleges of New York, 1948; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Faculty Freedom - Administratively Viewed (Chicago) (1955), Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 31)
- The Faculty Member as a Cultural Force in the Community, 1939; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 32)
- The Faith that Makes Men Whole, 1950-1951; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Faith: Toward the Wholeness of Man, 1964; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Faith in Our Time, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Speeches On First Principles of Higher Education, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Foreword to Dimock's Book, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Foreword to Collected Gideonse Papers - 1956, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Fort Worth Lectures, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 39)
- Four Basic Approaches to Ed. Admin., 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 40)
- Four Ways to Wisdom, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 41)
- Speeches on Democracy, 1940-1941; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 42)
- Ethics in Personnel Management, 1952-1968; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 43)
- The Discipline of Free Men, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 44)
- Education Toward Management, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 45)
- Democracy in Administration, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 46)
- Speeches Ideas and Clippings, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Speeches Ideas and Clippings, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Speeches Ideas and Clippings, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Intellectual Climate Syracuse and Cornell, Fall, 1957, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Freedom and Interferences in the Conduct of Education, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Freedom and Moral Relativism, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Freshman Thoughts, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Fruits of Scholarship, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Fundamental Contributions of YMCA, 1939; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Further Efforts to be Sententious, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Goals and Rewards in Education (Richmond - 1955), Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 11)
- The Goodness of Understanding, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Great Expectations, 1956; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Guiding Students in Troubled Times, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Happy Pagans or Committed Citizens, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Has Higher Education any Unifying Principles? (Bucknell), 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Speech Hazen Foundation Lectures, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 17)
- The Healthy Person's Creative Outlets, 1961; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Higher Education in the Days Ahead, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Higher Education and Philosophy of Life, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Higher Education and Philosophy of Life, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Higher Education and the Problem of Equality - 1955, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Higher Education for One World, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Higher Education as a Public Trust, 1961; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Higher Education: For Whom and for What? Hoffstra, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Higher Education for Higher Values (Syracuse, Pittsburgh 1957), Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Higher Goals for Higher Education, 1961; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 27)
- History and Philosophy of American Higher Education, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Hollins College, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Honor Systems, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 30)
- "Effectiveness in College Life" Hood College 2/2/49, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Honesty, Hypocrisy and Sex, 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 32)
- How Good are our Colleges?, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 33)
- How to Have Fun with Ideas, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 34)
- How to Realize Basic Educational Objectives (Little Six), Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 35)
- Human Desires and Satisfactions, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Human Values in Higher Education, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 37)
- Integrating Personnel and Teaching Functions in College - Raleigh, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Is There Inner Strength for Mental Troubles?, 1964; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 39)
- Introduction to Dimock's Book, Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 40)
- Integrity in the Relation of the College to it's Faculty (Review essay on Bixler's Book), Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Intensity in Tranquility, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 42)
- Informal Freshman Talks, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 10, Folder 43)
- Decision Making and Administration in Higher Education, 1958-1971; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 1)
- The Teacher's Personality: It's Richer Growth, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Quotable Ideas About Teaching, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Religious Topics, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Rauschenbusch Lectures, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 5)
- The Rediscovery of God, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 6)
- The Relation of Religion to Education, 1944; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Religion in Municipal College, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Quality in Teaching and in Learning, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Questions for a Religious Inquiry, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Speeches Religious Topics, 1966; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Religious Values and the Dramatic Faith, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Remembrance of Things Past, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Residence Workers, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Responsibility and Our Personal Potential, 1962; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Reviews "Art of Administration" - O. -Tead, 1951-1952; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Reviews of O.T. books Character Building and Higher Educations, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Reviews (The Climate of Learning) - O. Tead, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Richmond, Virginia Letter of Thanks, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 19)
- The Road Before Us for Our City Colleges, 1950-1953; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Rock Island - January 7, 1957, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Role of the Faculty in College Education, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Role of General Education in Junior College, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Role of Objectives in Higher Education, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Role of College Teacher in Our Culture, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 25)
- The Role of College Trustees and the Role of the College Trustee Today, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Roots of Teaching Power in American Culture, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 27)
- The Rounded Life - Tarrytown High School, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 28)
- College as Forwarder of Human Values, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 29)
- American Hospital Association (Chicago) August 1958, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Saturday Review - Tend, Editor, 1944; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Science Instruction in a Democracy, 1939; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 32)
- The Secular Campus and the Moral Decline, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Significant Issues in American Education, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 34)
- Social Patterns for Women, 1948-1955; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 35)
- Social Sciences and the Whole Man, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 36)
- Spiritual Problems of the Teachers, 1945; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 37)
- Spiritual Reality in Today's Perspective (Stuart Cole), 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 38)
- Standards of Quality from Survey Graphics, November, 1947, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 39)
- Steps Ahead in Higher Education, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 40)
- Stressing Human Values in Education, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 41)
- Survey Graphic - Educational Issues, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 42)
- Teacher Self-Evaluation, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 43)
- Teacher Self-Evaluation, Questions on, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 44)
- Speeches The Teacher and Teaching, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 45)
- A Star To Steer By, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 46)
- The Teacher's Design for Living, 1966; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 47)
- Teaching, Paragraphs on, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 48)
- Teaching, Quotable Ideas on, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 49)
- Ten Year Ahead in Higher Education, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 50)
- A Ten Year Look Ahead at the Liberal Arts College, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 51)
- Suggestions Toward Ten Commandments for All Who Have Personnel Relations with College Students, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 52)
- Tenure in New York City Colleges, Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 53)
- Terminal Courses in the Junior College (C.T.), Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 54)
- Thinking about Teaching, 1956; Black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 55)
- Misc. Short Greetings + Remarks, 1963; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Misc. Lectures to 1941, Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Human Desires and Satisfactions, Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Youth's Quest for Religion (A Layman Looks Ahead), 1952-1953; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Young People in the World Today, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 5)
- World mindedness: A Religious Dimension, 1964; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Women's Problems, 1948; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Speeches Women's Education, 1947-1948; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Why the Life of Mind?, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Why the Independent 2-Year College, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Women's Higher Education - Past, Present and Future, Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Why Liberal Colleges Tomorrow?, 1943; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Why is Christmas?, 1945; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 13)
- What is the Role of Art?, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 14)
- What's Ahead in the Colleges, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 15)
- What is your Community (Scarborough), 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 16)
- What is Life's Meaning? Hood Baccalaureate Address, 1961; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 17)
- What is Education?, Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 18)
- What is College For?, 1961; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 19)
- What Faith Will Make Men Whole?, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 20)
- What Difference Will Your College Education Make (Sweet Briar), 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 21)
- What are America's Purposes?, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 22)
- We are What We Do - Briarcliff January 1945, Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 23)
- Useful Words For College Teachers, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 24)
- Speeches - University of Texas, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 25)
- Lectures - University of Utah, 1951-1958; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 26)
- Speeches - University of Guatemala, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 27)
- Values Emphasis in Jr. College Teaching, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 28)
- Value Emphasis In College Teaching (Kentucky 1957), Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 29)
- The Troubled Student, Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Speeches University of Guatemala, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 31)
- Value Emphasis in Jr. College Training Grand Rapids, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 32)
- Value Emphasis in College Teaching (Kentucky 1957), Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 33)
- Trends in Curriculum Building, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 34)
- Two Year Colleges Their Promise for the Future Jamestown 1955, Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 35)
- Twelve Suggestions for Improving Teaching, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 36)
- Toward World Mindedness in College Education, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 37)
- Today's Challenge To Leadership, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 38)
- Addresses on Management + Administration, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 39)
- Toward the Knowledge of Man, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 40)
- The Word is: Work, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 41)
- Words and Deeds, 1943; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 42)
- Three Satisfactions Toward Teacher Self-Fulfillment, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 43)
- Toward First Principles in Higher Education, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 44)
- Thoughts Prompted By Student Testimony, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 45)
- Thoughts on Thinking Assembly January 23, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 46)
- This I Believe, Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 47)
- This Day We Sailed On, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 48)
- Thirteen Americans Other Copies in OT Autobiographical - Rear of General File, Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 49)
- Thinking As A fine Art, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 50)
- New Look in American Colleges, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 1)
- New Frontiers in Higher Education, Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 2)
- The Nature of Selfhood, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Speeches Municipal Education (Merton), 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Moral Emphasis in Education, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Mission of Liberal College Reinstated, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Speeches Miscellaneous Addresses, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 7)
- The Development of Leadership, 1942; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Message to Management, Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Creative Developments in Ind. Relations (Buffalo), Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Character Education for Business, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Speeches - Leadership, 1962; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 12)
- The Meaning of Scholarship, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 13)
- The Meaning of Residence Work, Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Meaning of College, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 15)
- The Meaning of the Library (Briarcliff Library Dedication), 1964; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 16)
- The Marriage of Thought and Action, Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Major Issues in Today's Higher Education, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Making Leadership Effective on the Campus (Trenton 1956), Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 19)
- The Lube of Learning (Randolph Macon 1957), Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 20)
- The Lure of Learning, 1956; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Looking Ahead at the Role of the College San Francisco State College, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Look at their Faces, Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Eduard C. Lindeman, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Life, Liberty and the Pursuit of Power, 1942; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 25)
- A Liberal Education: A Definition, Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 26)
- The Liberal College Ten Years Hence (Buffalo), Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Liberal Arts At Hood College, 1968; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 28)
- The Learning Process, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 29)
- Leadership for Responsibility and Creativity (1958), Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 30)
- Learning as The Revelation of Reality, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 31)
- Leadership and Personality Growth, Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 32)
- Layman's View of Place of Religion in Public Education, 1944; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 33)
- Knowledge, Action and Social Research, 1940; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 34)
- Knowledge and Action, 1943; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 35)
- Junior College Teaching Challenge or Dilemma, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 36)
- A Junior College for Your Daughter?, 1944; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 37)
- Junior Colleges - Their Role in Liberal Arts Education, Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 38)
- Junior College Contribution, 1944; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 39)
- Junior College Teaching: Challenge or Dilemma? (LaSalle), 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 40)
- Justifying The Junior College, 1944; Black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 41)
- O. Tead - Lecture Prospecting, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
- O. tead - Lecture Prospectus (1958), Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Passion, Principle and Persuasion, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Pathways to A Full Life - New Paltz, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Paragraphs on Teaching, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Public Mindedness Through Cooperation, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Problems of Administration in a Democratic Society, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Problem of First Principles in Higher Education, 1948; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Problem of first Principles In Higher Education, 1948; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 9)
- President's Commission, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Point of No Return, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Pleasantville Rotary Club April 1955, Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Place of Philosophy in Postwar Education, 1944; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Place of Characters Education in College, Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Philosophic Unification and the College Curriculum, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Personnel Mgt. and Public Relations in College, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Personality in Church Administration, 1964; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Behind the Faade, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Assuring Learning through teaching in the First Two Years, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Assuring Learning Through Teaching, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Aspects of Human Equality, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 21)
- On Being A Chairman, Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Orienting Business Education After the War, 1943; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 23)
- The Outlets for Creativity, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 24)
- Speeches Portrait of the Graduate, 1969; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 25)
- PTA Papers, Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 26)
- Publisher and the People, Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Periodical Articles by O.T., 1952-1954; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 28)
- Personal Leadership - How is it Made Effective, 1939-1940; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 29)
- New Perspectives on the Administrator's Job, Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 30)
- New Reflections in Old Mirrors, Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 31)
- New York Unesco Conference, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 32)
- N.Y. University Graduate School of Edu. The Private Two Year College March 21, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 33)
- New York University Speech Publishing Business, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 34)
- Problems of Administration with a Democratic Society - June, 7. 1951 - Looks Like Speech, Black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 35)
- Bank Statements - 1967-1968, Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Master List, Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
- American Institute of Management, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Advancing the Public Interest in Labor Relations, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Approaches to Modern Teaching, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Bridging the Gulf Between Liberal and Vocational Education, 1945; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Questions for a Religious Inquiry, Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Questions for a Religious Inquiry, Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Questions on College Teaching, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 9)
- The Science of Administration in the International world, Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Thinking is A Fine Art, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 11)
- What Difference Will Your College Education Make?, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Young People in the World Today, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Carbon Copies of Speeches, 1948; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 14)
- The Role of Objectives in Higher Education, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Looking Ahead at the Role of the College, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 16)